# Aleksei Nechaev

### Software Developer



https://www.linkedin.com/in/alekseinechaev77/

(513) 282-9605

aleksei.snech77@gmail.com

Hard-working professional with 3 years of experience in JavaScript, a proven knowledge of extensive experience using HTML/CSS gained through creating a multitude of websites. In addition, have over 2 years of experience using Java. Aiming to leverage programming skills to successfully fill the Software Developer role.



### **Skills**

• Experience in SQL

Excellent

Experience in JavaScript

•••• Excellent

• Experience in CSS

Excellent

Experience in HTML

••••• Excellent

Experience in Java

Excellent



## **Work History**

### IT Tutor With Experience in HTML/CSS, JavaScript

WyzAnt Tutoring, Mason, OH

- Collaborated with students to complete homework assignments, identify lagging skills and correct weaknesses.
- Helped students prepare for tests and exams by providing guidance, motivation and encouragement.
- Developed student confidence through positive reinforcement strategies.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery languages

#### Freelancer

Upwork.com

2022-04 - Current

2021-11 - Current

2018-02 - 2018-03

Was helping client on making optimizing web page and client's content to be easily discoverable by users searching using Wordpress.

#### Volunteer

High School, Cincinnati, OH

- Tutored one student on how to align menu items horizontally centered in the header. I used some learning strategies. For example, I implemented fun and educational activities to make the student feel comfortable in an online classroom. This was because environmental factors can affect critical thinking which is very important in programming. The student is now able to align menu items correctly.
- Volunteered with groups and organizations to help make measurable differences for program recipients.
- Engaged in community outreach to support program mission.



### **Education**

 Bachelor Of Science In Information Technology: Computer Software And Media Applications

University of Cincinnati - Cincinnati, OH

- Associate of Applied Science: Information Technology
  University of Cincinnati Blue Ash College Cincinnati, OH
- High School Diploma
  William Mason High School Mason, OH



### Languages

English



Russian





### **Certifications**

- Learning Relational Databases
- Python for Students
- Succeeding in Web Development: Full Stack and Front End
- IT Security Foundations: Core Concepts
- Programming Foundations: Databases
- CompTIA A+ (220-1001) Cert Prep 7: Understanding Networking
- CompTIA A+ (220-1001) Cert Prep 8: Internet and the Cloud
- CompTIA A+ (220-1002) Cert Prep 4: Command-Line Interface and Scripting Languages
- Excel Essential Training (Office 365/Microsoft 365)
- CompTIA A+ (220-1001) Cert Prep 1: The Basics

# 2022-05 - 2024-05

2020-08 - Current

2017-08 - 2020-05

2020-10 2020-10

2020-10

2020-12 2020-11

2020-10 2020-10

2020-10

2020-09

2020-09 2020-09 2020-09 2020-09 2020-09

- CompTIA A+ (220-1001) Cert Prep 2: Microprocessing and RAM
- CompTIA A+ (220-1001) Cert Prep 3: Core Hardware
- CompTIA A+ (220-1001) Cert Prep 6: Physical Networking
- CompTIA A+ (220-1002) Cert Prep 8: Security and Organization
- Word 2019 Essential Training